hey everyone welcome back to another
interesting Tosca lesson today I am
going to talk about how you can perform
a tql search and how you can store them
in different virtual folders
now coming to tql it stands for Tosca
query language and using this uh you can
basically construct different uh complex
queries using this tql search you can do
complex search on your workspace and it
will return you with all the different
objects which matches that search
criteria okay
so uh talking about search in Tosca
there are obviously two options when you
go into the menu on the top you will see
that is the search
and everything is integrated in this one
window okay so you have got two types of
search here simple antiquel
and you have also got an option to
directly uh store your tql search into a
virtual folder on the right hand side
okay
so when you do a simple search it is
just entering some text and then trying
to find what objects are associated or
are a match for this particular text
okay so if I click on search now
it will return me all the objects which
are a match for this particular text
okay so that's simple search nothing too
spectacular about it but when you come
to tql search uh that simple search is
now converted into a query language okay
which is defined by Tosca it has its own
grammar and operators so if you want to
use this you have to understand uh some
things about this particular query
language okay now the equal search
queries tend to consist of many sub
Expressions so you can see this is a
expression then the sub parts is an
expression and then this is like a
logical expression where we are
comparing or we are using this operators
equals to question mark where it
searches for all the different objects
which contain this particular text okay
so if I want to change this search a
little bit and if I make this a name
equals equals Google you will see the
lesson number of results which are
displayed now and that is because it
will try to search for an exact match uh
previously it was not an exact match it
was just uh any particular object which
contains this particular text okay so
that's how you can basically play around
with this SQL search query
now let me show you another example
where a search could be useful in terms
of your executions right so if you want
to find out if your executions
um all the test cases have passed or
failed or does the execution list
contain any test cases or not right so
things like these you can easily search
through a tql okay so these are
basically uh some logical kind of search
and not uh any typical search which you
can do through a simple search right so
for this uh let's try and use this
subparts okay we are in the root folder
so it will display all the subparts
which contain this particular or which
basically satisfy this search criteria
so we are going to look for execution
list here okay
and then here you can see that it shows
me all the execution lists which are
present in this particular workspace
okay using the sub parts
and these are all the execution lists
which are present currently okay now if
I want to filter out this results which
is currently shown here you can see
there are number of different options
okay
um and there I can see number of test
cases failed number of test cases passed
so what I can do I can do this search
like number of test cases passed is
greater than one
okay
and then if I search it will return me
this result where this particular test
case uh or execution list has got a
number of test cases passed greater than
one okay and similarly I can say number
of test cases failed okay equals to zero
or I can say
um
less than one okay
and it will give me uh three different
uh execution list where number of test
cases failed is less than one which
means most of the test cases have passed
okay so things like this uh you can do a
SQL search based on you can do it on
requirements on modules on test step
values on execution lists on test cases
right so whatever you want to do you can
do it using this SQL search you just
need to get used to
um this structure how this Tosca query
language is structured with different
sub expressions and operators so you
just need to take care of that and then
it will find you all the objects for you
okay
foreign
folder now virtual folders as the name
suggests uh it it doesn't have any
linked to any particular or any assigned
objects it only contains the search
function okay so whatever results you
are getting from the tql search it will
be displayed in a virtual folder so you
can save the results in this particular
folder and then whenever you want you
can go there and you can fetch the
latest results from the workspace
so it's basically it's easier to access
your search results rather than going
into that equal search and always
entering a particular search query and
then looking for the results you can go
to that virtual folder and you can
directly open that okay
so let's go ahead and see how we can
basically create a virtual folder uh at
any place so you can create a virtual
folder except the root folder or the
root project right you can create it at
any folder level or baby be it execution
modules requirements test cases now
reason I cannot save this as indirectly
into virtual folder is because I am in
the root project okay so you cannot save
it here so the other way around is go to
a particular folder like test cases
and then here let's create a virtual
folder so when you right click on any
particular folder there will be a option
to create a virtual folder click on that
and then it will ask you to rename it
you can or you it's not necessary to
rename that virtual folder but if you
have many virtual folders it's better to
rename it okay
now the most important part of virtual
folder or the most important requirement
is to enter a query which is basically
your tql query right so when you go to
properties and open that it will ask you
to enter a particular SQL query right
so let's see what we can build here okay
so I am in the test cases folder so I
will use the sub paths
and then I will use this time the test
case okay
and inside test case what I want to see
is what test cases were created by me
okay
now this will be useful when you have
got a number of different users in your
workspace okay if you want to see uh who
has created how many test cases so that
could be a good report for the
management team right so you can provide
this report directly from this virtual
folder okay so you can easily see who
has created how many test cases and you
can even see when it was created by just
editing this query okay so here uh it is
uh I am the admin user here so I'll say
created by equals equals admin and then
I will click on OK and you will see a
list of different test cases uh being
shown here okay so you can see there are
so many test cases which are now
contained in this virtual folder okay
now
um I can even
modify this okay you can also always get
the latest results by right clicking and
clicking on this refresh virtual folder
so if something has changed it will not
automatically change in the virtual
folder you need to refresh it okay so
once you refresh it you will get the
latest results here you can always edit
the query from here you can also create
a report from virtual folder we'll see
that later but if you have a virtual
folder you can create a report there
will be an option to do that okay
so that's all the usage of a virtual
folder how you can create it and how you
can use it okay now you can do a lot of
other things as I said uh you can even
filter this results based on uh if the
test cases was marked as complete if it
was a template if it is not been
completed how many has been completed
like so many things you can do with this
virtual folders so you can create a
number of different virtual folders and
then for analyzing the results or
reporting the results you can use this
virtual folders which you can then bring
into your reports okay
so that's all about that equal search
and how to create virtual folders and
how to use it hope it was helpful and
look out for more interesting videos
coming up uh very pretty soon